kansan.com 2002-06-07

# Kansan.com - Privacy Policy and Internet Safety Tips

**KANSAN.COM'S PRIVACY POLICY AND INTERNET SAFETY INFORMATION**

Kansan.com is committed to providing the best online campus experience within a trusted environment. Privacy and safety issues are important to us. We clearly state our privacy policy and at the end of this document you will find some important internet safety tips.

**PRIVACY POLICY**

**Question regarding our policies**

Questions regarding our policies should be directed to our web editor by e-mail at [webeditor@kansan.com](mailto:webeditor@kansan.com), or by phone at (785) 864-4810, or by postal mail at: Kansan.com ATTN: Privacy Policy Coordinator 119 Stauffer-Flint Hall, Lawrence, KS 66045.

**The Internet, Privacy, and Kansan.com**

The Internet contains a wealth of information, unfortunately, it may also contain personal details about you that you don't want everyone to know. For example, your real name (lots of people on the Internet use aliases, alter egos or nicknames), street address, phone number, or e-mail address. When you go online, sites you visit may be gathering information about you without your knowledge. At Kansan.com we strive to help our customers protect their privacy while using our services.

**Kansan.com's Privacy Policy**

Kansan.com's policy is to respect and protect the privacy of our users. This policy statement tells you how we collect information from you and how we use it. Using the Internet should be a fun experience and we want to help you make it so.

The information you provide for your personal Kansan.com account will not be discloses to third parties without your consent. Kansan.com may disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Kansan.com's rights or property, other Kansan.com users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Kansan.com may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

Kansan.com shares aggregate information about our users with advertisers, business partners, sponsors and other third parties. For example, we will say Kansan.com's audience is x percent females and y percent males. This data is used to customize Kansan.com content and advertising to deliver a better experience for our users.

There are cases where Kansan.com may ask you for personal information such as your name, e-mail address, and birth date. For example, we request personal information when you register for a Kansan.com account or for services that require registration or subscription. Kansan.com needs to collect this information for fulfilling prizes, tracking/verifying compliance with Kansan.com policies as well as federal, state and local laws and/or for editorial and feedback solicitation purposes.

In case you change your mind or some personal information may change (such as your zip code), we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove the personal data you give us. You can do this by contacting us via e-mail at [info@kansan.com](mailto:info@kansan.com).

**Opting-Out**

Information provided at the time of Registration or submission from a guest who is 18 years of age or over may be used for marketing and promotional purposes by Kansan.com and our affiliates or companies that have been prescreened by Kansan.com. To keep you in control of your personal information and the communications directed to you, we allow you to opt-out of the following services: sharing your information in our member directory, receiving communications from Kansan.com about new features or services, and receiving communications about offers from third-party companies that offer a product or service that we think would be of value to you. If a guest objects to such use for any reason, he/she may stop that use -- by e-mail request to [info@kansan.com](mailto:info@kansan.com).

Information provided when purchasing products from any of our online stores may be used for marketing and promotional purposes and is subject to the opt-out processes described on, or linked to, each order form.

**Policies for Kids and Teens (Individuals Under 18 years of Age)**

Kansan.com encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered on the sites. No information should be submitted to or posted at Kansan.com by guests under 17 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian.

Guests under 18 years of age may not participate in any contests or promotions offered by Kansan.com sites.

**Use of IP Address**

An IP address is a number that's automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the Web. Web servers -- the big computers that "serve up" Web pages -- automatically identify your computer by its IP address.

Kansan.com collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to our advertisers, and to audit the use of our site. When guests request pages from Kansan.com sites, our servers log the guests' IP addresses. We do not normally link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that a user's session will be logged, but the user remains anonymous to us. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our house rules or terms of service or to protect our service, site, customers or others.

Some services within Kansan.com, such as certain message boards, may display IP addresses along with the message poster's name and message. Please review each service prior to use and only use those that disclose information you are comfortable with sharing.

**Use of Cookies**

What are cookies? Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to an individual's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies make Web-surfing easier for you by saving your preferences while you're at our site. We never save passwords or credit card information in cookies. The use of cookies is an industry standard -- you'll find them at most major Web sites.

By showing how and when guests use a site, cookies help us see which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the site are based on such data as total number of visitors and pages viewed. This information is most easily tracked with cookies. We use the information from cookies to provide services better tailored to our users needs.

You may occasionally get cookies from our advertisers. Kansan.com does not control these cookies. The use of advertising cookies sent by third-party servers is standard in the Internet industry.

**Links to Other Sites**

Users should be aware that when you are on Kansan.com, you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control. There are links to other sites from Kansan.com pages that take you outside our service. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement or an Kansan.com search result, the "click" takes you off the Kansan.com site. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use Kansan.com's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data or solicit personal information.

Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information online --- for example, via message boards or chat --- that information can be collected and used by people you don't know. While Kansan.com strives to protect its user's personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online and you do so at your own risk.

Kansan.com's policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond Kansan.com's control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation.

**Security**

The importance of security for all personally identifiable information associated with our guests is of utmost concern to us. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Kansan.com can't ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. When credit card information is transmitted we use industry standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption.

**Your Acceptance of These Terms**

By using this site, you signify your assent to the Kansan.com Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our sites. Your continued use of the Kansan.com sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

Last Updated 2/9/2000

Back to top

**SAFETY TIPS**  
This is a great place for both new and advanced Web users to find information on using the Internet wisely. 

**Some Internet Safety Tips**

  1. Keep your passwords private, even from your best friend! Your online service will never ask for them, so neither should anyone else. 
  2. Use only your member name and/or e-mail address when chatting or sending e-mail. Never give out personal information like your name, address, or phone number. Anyone with your phone number can easily find out your name and address. 
  3. Always delete unknown e-mail attachments before opening them. They can contain destructive viruses. 
  4. Remember that nothing you write on the Web is completely private \- including e-mail. So be careful and think about what you type and who you tell. 
  5. Not everyone is as nice, cute and funny as they may sound online. Never make plans to meet an online "friend" in person. 

**More Safety Information**

  1. [Cybernetiquette Comix](http://disney.go.com/cybersafety/index.html) \- an entertaining, interactive way for families to learn valuable lessons about online safety. Join classic Disney characters for adventure, fun, and online awareness tips. 
  2. [Disney's Doug](http://disney.go.com/disneytelevision/onesaturdaymorning/doug/tips/dougtips.html) \- Safety Tips from "Doug's Adventures Online" 
  3. [Test Your Internet Smarts](http://apps.disney.go.com/global/quiz/quiz.cgi?def=doug1) \- How much do you know about Internet safety? 
  4. [More Top 10 Netiquette Tips](http://disney.go.com/cybersafety/tips2.html) \- An overview of good manners on the Internet. 
  5. "[Safe and Sound](http://family.disney.go.com/Features/family_1998_03/dony/dony38safety/dony38safety.html)" - An Internet safety article from Family.com. 
  6. [Safe Surfing for Kids](http://family.go.com/Features/family_1997_07/famp/famp77savvypooh/famp77savvypooh.html) \- An Internet safety article from FamilyPC Magazine. 

Back to top
